JACKSON ROBBINS

jackson@jacksonr.com | (312) 429-7345 | www.linkedin.com/in/jacksonrobbins606 | jacksonr.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full stack web developer and literal "Jack of all trades." I offer a wide range of expertise from prior roles that encompass sales, marketing, operations, customer support, and most recently software development. From my extensive experience in customer facing roles, I am skilled at understanding the technology needs of customers or stakeholders and communicating solutions in simple and relatable terms. I am a lifelong learner who enjoys studying complex systems and solving problems.

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Working Knowledge: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Restful API Systems, SQL, Linux Ubuntu & CentOS, Ionic, Angular, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material Design Lite, Git, Node.js, FreshDesk, Trello, Invision, Google Suite

Primal Portal — <u>Demo</u> | <u>Code</u>

Web portal for Chicago Primal Gym members to record and view their personal records with interactive dashboards

- Built back end with Ruby on Rails set-up as a RESTFUL API and hosted on Heroku
- Created front end with React and used Material-UI for styling the interface and React Router for user navigation
- Generated interactive animated charts using Uber's react-vis library
- Implemented secure login and user authentication using JSON web tokens and bcrypt

Grumbler — Code

WebApp to search and view food inspection records for every Chicago restaurant

- Utilized Google Cloud Services to enable users to find restaurants with a "Googly" search bar with relevant results
- Used Chicago's Data Portal and Food Inspection Records API to show inspection records for Chicago restaurants
- Styled front end of app with Semantic UI React

AMOpportunities — https://www.amopportunities.org/

Online marketplace for foreign medical students to explore and enroll in medical rotations in the United States.

- Developed the front-end of AMO's web and mobile app using Ionic and Angular.
- Collaborated with AMO's various teams to gather input for the app and implement needed design changes.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AMOpportunities — Chicago, IL

Junior Web Developer

July 2018 — November 2018

- AMO develops an online platform that connects healthcare providers with medical students seeking clinical rotations.
- Developed the front-end of AMO's web and mobile app using Ionic.
- Worked alongside AMO's various teams to gather input and design custom components for the app's UX / UI.

TouchBistro — Chicago, IL

July 2017 — October 2017

Customer Care Specialist

Toronto-based tech company that develops a restaurant point of sale (POS) system for the iPad.

- Handle Tier 1 customer support requests from inbound calls, emails, and tickets.
- Assist clients with account options, ongoing subscriptions / billing, and troubleshooting technical issues
- Created documentation for the support team's procedures to improve the quality and consistency of customer service.

<u>DialogTech</u> — Chicago, IL

May 2016 — January 2017

Account Development Representative of call attribution technology

Chicago-based tech company that develops inbound call tracking software for digital marketers.

- Worked with business dev. team to execute prospecting strategy built from multi-channel marketing data.
- Informed potential clients about our software and how the data it gathers can improve and integrate with their systems.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School — Chicago, IL

April 2019 — July 2019

• 15 week full-time coding bootcamp that teaches full-stack web development

Macalester College — St. Paul, MN

August 2008 — May 2012

• Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology (GPA: 3.10)

Associated Colleges of the Midwest: Costa Rica Field Research ProgramJanuary 2011 — May 2011